Adam Maen

Software Engineer with hands-on experience in fields such as machine learning, data science and Web development.

adam.maen01@gmail.com
In:linkedin.com/in/maen1/
Github: github.com/Maen1

Phone#: +46 735 720 821

About me *********

I have been actively programming for more than 6 years in multiple fields while doing my degrees, I worked at several start-ups and learn a lot about how to start a business from scratch as well as wearing different hats based on the task in hand. I enjoy solving problems and working either within a team or independent.

Skills *********

Data Science

Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-Learn, Scipy, Pandas, SimpleITK, OpenCV, imageio, Matplotlib and Numpy...), C++ Familiar with Spark, Hadoop and ROS.

Web Development

Php (Laravel), JavaScript (VueJS), HTML, CSS (Tailwind, Bootstrap, Bulma), MySQL and Redis.

DevOps

Docker, OOP, MVC, TDD, UNIX shell, GIT and GCP.

Work Experience ****

Machine Vision Engineer

Antaros Medical AB | Uppsala, Sweden | Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

- Built multiple deep learning models for Whole-body lesions segmentation in 3D PET/CT.
- Experimenting with 3D volumes images (Enhancement, Extraction and Visualization)

Co-founder and Software Engineer

MySenior | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Jan 2019 - Jan 2021

• Built an end-to-end online educational service that helps students find tutors within their university communities.

Data Scientist

TM R&D | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Feb 2020 - Aug 2020

- Trained machine learning model to identify employees and integrate it with a thermal imagining system to build an attendance system that registers employees' check-in/out and their temperature.
- Collected data and trained machine learning model to detect heavy machinery vehicles in construction sites with camera setup on Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) and send the coordination to a server.

Research Assistant

IIUM | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

- Worked with my supervisor by applying Machine Vision and deep learning in the medical field, especially with x-ray images.
- Published two papers about data integrity and the thresh hold of human error in labelling the data to get a valuable machine learning model.
- Built a web-based application to segment lung cancer in 2D medical images.

Software Engineer (Freelance)

Online | Worldwide | Jun 2016 - Feb 2020

- Built multiple websites for organizations and individual businesses in different categories (NGOs, Educational, Small businesses and Personal websites)
- Did many internships in start-ups with different fields such as Robotics and Saas.

Education ********

Master in Image Analysis and Machine Learning

Uppsala University | Uppsala, Sweden | Aug 2020 - Jun 2022

Program website

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours)

IIUM | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Feb 2016 - Aug 2020

Program website

Online Courses *****

Specializations on Coursera

- Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) | (3 courses) | Jun 2021
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate (10 courses) | Sept 2019
- Deep Learning | (5 Courses) | Oct 2018
 - 20+ other courses in machine learning and software engineering list in LinkedIn profile.

Activities ********

ICPC Asia Singapore Regional

- International Collegiate Programming Contest(ICPC) is an algorithmic programming contest for college students
- to Represent Malaysia after passing the qualification national (Malaysia) and the virtual regional (India).

3 Days of Code

- Indvial contest and hackathon joined by all Malaysian universities.
- Ranked 3rd in the contest.

Nasa Space App Challenge

- Team based competition of two days hackathon
- We build a machine learning model to predict missed data from satellite sensors.

Volunteered as a trainer and conducted robotics and web development workshops for junior students.

Languages *********

```
English (Fluent)
Arabic (Fluent)
Turkish (Intermediate)
Swedish (Learning)
```